Rhiannon: There are times when everyone
feels the strain and Covid 19 has
affected all of us in some way, either
through being in lockdown or losing a
friend or family member to the virus.
For children and young people however,
the changes have been really dramatic
challenging everything they’ve grown
to understand to be normal in life.
Leah: Some children and young people
may have enjoyed not going to school,
while others will have really struggled
with the coronavirus outbreak keeping
them at home and away from friends.
Others may be coming to terms with
family problems, loss or changes to
their living situation and not being able
to see family members for a long time.
Rhiannon: Having to self-isolate,
due to a class or school outbreak
or periods of school closures have
created many uncertainties to many
children and young people about
their education and their futures.
Leah: Coronavirus has impacted
everyone in many different ways
and mental health is one of those.
This pandemic can be seen as a medical
crisis now but also a mental health crisis
going forward and will have a great impact
on the mental health of many children
and young people in the years to come.